<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on KonFound-It!</title>
    <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on KonFound-It!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://konfound-project.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</guid>
      <description>by Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, Ran Xu, Spiro Maroulis, Guan Saw, &amp;amp; Josh Rosenberg&#xA;Last updated: 8/13/2023&#xA;Introduction This document addresses some frequently asked questions regarding KonFound. See the appendices for background readings and software. For quick reference, see:&#xA;Overview of all KonFound commands Main introductory slides for combined frameworks Background There are two basic frameworks for sensitivity analysis employed within KonFound. First is the Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable (ITCV)—Frank (2000).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</guid>
      <description>Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient. Sociological Methods and Research, 29(2), 147-194. PDF | Web&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., &amp;amp; Maroulis, S. (2023). Quantifying sensitivity to selection on unobservables: Refining Oster’s coefficient of proportionality. White paper. PDF&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., Maroulis, S., Mueller, A. S., Xu, R., Rosenberg, J. M., Hayter, C. S., Mahmoud, R. A., Kolak, M., Dietz, T.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource Overview</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Explanatory Resources FAQ Overview of pkonfound commands Quick examples Powerpoint quantifying the robustness of causal inferences combined frameworks Powerpoint for comparison of frameworks Additional Resources for Publication Published empirical examples Spreadsheet for calculating indices (KonFound-it!) Publications: Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient. Sociological Methods and Research, 29(2), 147-194. PDF | Web Frank, K. A., Sykes, G.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Talks Quantifying Sensitivity to Selection on Unobservables: Refining Oster’s Coefficient of Proportionality Association for Education Finance and Policy&#xA;March 15, 2024 (8:00am–9:45am Eastern time, Baltimore Marriott Waterfront, Room 12 — Falkland)&#xA;Paper&#xA;Quantifying the Robustness of Causal Inferences: Sensitivity Analysis for Pragmatic Social Science Emory University: Workshop on Advanced Research Methods&#xA;March 21, 2024 (8:30pm–9:30pm Eastern time, Virtual)&#xA;Paper&#xA;Robustness of Inference to Replacement &amp;amp; Fragility for Logistic Regression and Hazard Functions Michigan State University Biostats</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</guid>
      <description> Under construction, but coming soon </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Workshops University of Arizona Computational Social Science&#xA;February 14, 2024 (2:30pm–5:00pm Mountain time). In-person: Tempe, AZ.&#xA;Statistical Horizons Two Key Techniques for Quantifying the Robustness of Causal Inferences&#xA;February 29–March 1, 2024 (2-day mini-course). Virtual.&#xA;Association for Education Finance and Policy What would it take to Change your Inference? Informing Discourse about Causal Inferences in the Educational Ecosystem&#xA;March 5, 2024 (12:00pm–3:00pm Eastern time). Virtual.&#xA;American Educational Research Association What Would It Take to Change Your Inference?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
