<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on KonFound-It!</title>
    <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on KonFound-It!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://konfound-project.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</guid>
      <description>by Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, Ran Xu, Spiro Maroulis, Guan Saw, &amp;amp; Josh Rosenberg&#xA;Last updated: 7/5/2024&#xA;FAQ Dev Version&#xA;Introduction This document addresses some frequently asked questions regarding KonFound. See the appendices for background readings and software. For quick reference, see:&#xA;Overview of all KonFound commands Main introductory slides for combined frameworks Background There are two basic frameworks for sensitivity analysis employed within KonFound. First is the Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable (ITCV)—Frank (2000).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</guid>
      <description>Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient. Sociological Methods and Research, 29(2), 147-194. PDF | Web&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., &amp;amp; Maroulis, S. (2023). Quantifying sensitivity to selection on unobservables: Refining Oster’s coefficient of proportionality. White paper. PDF&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., Maroulis, S., Mueller, A. S., Xu, R., Rosenberg, J. M., Hayter, C. S., Mahmoud, R. A., Kolak, M.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource Overview</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Tools R package (CRAN version) R package (development version) R Shiny app Stata package Benchmarks: What Works Clearinghouse [BETA] Explanatory Resources FAQ Overview of KonFound techniques Overview of KonFound commands Quick examples Slides quantifying the robustness of causal inferences combined frameworks Slides for comparison of frameworks Resources for Publication Published empirical examples KonFound-It! spreadsheet for calculating indices Publications: Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Talks Quantifying Sensitivity to Selection on Unobservables: Refining Oster’s Coefficient of Proportionality Joint Statistcal Meetings&#xA;August 4, 2024 (8:30pm–9:30pm Pacific time).&#xA;Paper&#xA;Past Talks Robustness of Inference to Replacement &amp;amp; Fragility for Logistic Regression and Hazard Functions University of Gothenburg, Sweden. School of Public Health&#xA;May 23, 2024 (1:00pm–2:45pm Sweden time).&#xA;Paper&#xA;Robustness of Inference to Replacement &amp;amp; Fragility for Logistic Regression and Hazard Functions Michigan State University Biostats</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User Guide</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</guid>
      <description> Under construction, but coming soon </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Workshops Academy of Management What Would it Take to Change an Inference? Sensitivity Analysis to Inform Innovation in the Future&#xA;August 9, 2024 (8:00am–11:00am Central time). In-person: Chicago, IL.&#xA;Past Workshops Society for Epidemiological Research What would it take to change your inference? Quantifying the Discourse about Causal Inferences in Epidemiology&#xA;July 24, 2024 (8:30am–12:30pm Central time). Virtual.&#xA;Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) Sensitivity Analysis: Quantifying the Robustness of Inferences to Alternative Factors or Data</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
