<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on KonFound-It!</title>
    <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on KonFound-It!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://konfound-project.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</guid>
      <description>by Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, Ran Xu, Spiro Maroulis, Guan Saw, &amp;amp; Josh Rosenberg&#xA;Last updated: 7/5/2024&#xA;FAQ Dev Version&#xA;Introduction This document addresses some frequently asked questions regarding KonFound. See the appendices for background readings and software. For quick reference, see:&#xA;Overview of all KonFound commands Main introductory slides for combined frameworks Background There are two basic frameworks for sensitivity analysis employed within KonFound. First is the Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable (ITCV)—Frank (2000).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Guide</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</guid>
      <description>PDF Download: April 2025 Practical Guide draft&#xA;Citation: *Frank, K. A., *Saw, G. K., Lin, Q., Xu, R., Rosenberg, J. M., Maroulis, S. J., &amp;amp; Staudt Willet, K. B. (2025). A practical guide to impact threshold of a confounding variable (ITCV) and robustness of inference to replacement (RIR). Michigan State University.&#xA;* Co first authors.&#xA;Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; / [pdf] View the PDF file here. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</guid>
      <description>Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient. Sociological Methods and Research, 29(2), 147-194. PDF | Web&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., &amp;amp; Maroulis, S. (2023). Quantifying sensitivity to selection on unobservables: Refining Oster’s coefficient of proportionality. White paper. PDF&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., Maroulis, S., Mueller, A. S., Xu, R., Rosenberg, J. M., Hayter, C. S., Mahmoud, R. A., Kolak, M.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource Overview</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Tools R package (CRAN version) R package (development version) R Shiny app Stata package Benchmarks: What Works Clearinghouse [BETA] Explanatory Resources FAQ Overview of KonFound techniques Overview of KonFound commands Quick examples Slides quantifying the robustness of causal inferences combined frameworks Slides for comparison of frameworks Resources for Publication Published empirical examples KonFound-It! spreadsheet for calculating indices Publications: Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Talks Quantifying Sensitivity to Selection on Unobserved Covariates: Recasting the Coefficient of Proportionality within a Correlational Framework 2025 Joint Statistical Meetings, Multi-faceted Approaches to Sensitivity Analysis for Observational Studies&#xA;August 6, 2025 (10:30am–12:30pm Central time in Nashville, TN).&#xA;Paper&#xA;Presenters: Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, &amp;amp; Spiro Maroulis&#xA;Abstract: Sensitivity analyses can inform evidence-based education policy by quantifying the hypothetical conditions necessary to change an inference. Perhaps the most prevalent index used for sensitivity analyses is Oster’s (2019) Coefficient of Proportionality (COP).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Workshops Society for Epidemiological Research What Would it Take to Change Your Inference? Quantifying the Discourse about Causal Inferences in Epidemiology&#xA;August 5, 2025 (12:00–4:00pm Eastern time). Virtual.&#xA;Description:&#xA;Causal inferences are often challenged because of uncontrolled bias. We will turn concerns about potential bias into questions about how much bias there must be to invalidate an inference. For example, challenges such as ‘But the inference of an exposure might not be valid because of pre-existing differences between the treatment groups’ are transformed to questions such as ‘How much bias must there have been due to uncontrolled pre-existing differences to make the inference invalid?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
