<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on KonFound-It!</title>
    <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on KonFound-It!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://konfound-project.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</guid>
      <description>by Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, Ran Xu, Spiro Maroulis, Guan Saw, &amp;amp; Josh Rosenberg&#xA;Last updated: 7/5/2024&#xA;FAQ Dev Version&#xA;Introduction This document addresses some frequently asked questions regarding KonFound. See the appendices for background readings and software. For quick reference, see:&#xA;Overview of all KonFound commands Main introductory slides for combined frameworks Background There are two basic frameworks for sensitivity analysis employed within KonFound. First is the Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable (ITCV)—Frank (2000).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Guide</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</guid>
      <description>PDF Download: Practical Guide (August 2025 version)&#xA;Citation: *Frank, K. A., *Saw, G. K., Lin, Q., Xu, R., Rosenberg, J. M., Maroulis, S. J., &amp;amp; Staudt Willet, K. B. (2025). A practical guide to impact threshold of a confounding variable (ITCV) and robustness of inference to replacement (RIR). Michigan State University.&#xA;* Co first authors.&#xA;Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; / [pdf] View the PDF file here. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</guid>
      <description>2025 Frank, K. A. (2025). Sensitivity to attrition for inferences from an RCT. Paper presented at the Meeting of the Society for Causal Inference (Detroit, MI, May 2025). Web&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., &amp;amp; Maroulis, S., Dai, S., Jess, N., Lin, H.-C., Liu, Y., Maestrales, S., Searle, E., &amp;amp; Tait, J. (2025). Quantifying sensitivity to selection on unobserved covariates: Recasting the coefficient of proportionality within a correlational framework. Preprint.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource Overview</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Tools R package (CRAN version) R package (development version) R Shiny app Stata package Benchmarks: What Works Clearinghouse [BETA] Explanatory Resources FAQ Overview of KonFound techniques Overview of KonFound commands Quick examples Slides quantifying the robustness of causal inferences combined frameworks Slides for comparison of frameworks Resources for Publication Published empirical examples KonFound-It! spreadsheet for calculating indices Publications: Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Talks Check back again soon for news about more talks!&#xA;Past Talks Quantifying Sensitivity to Selection on Unobserved Covariates: Recasting the Coefficient of Proportionality within a Correlational Framework 2025 Joint Statistical Meetings, Multi-faceted Approaches to Sensitivity Analysis for Observational Studies&#xA;August 6, 2025 (10:30am–12:30pm Central time in Nashville, TN).&#xA;Paper&#xA;Presenters: Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, &amp;amp; Spiro Maroulis&#xA;Abstract: Sensitivity analyses can inform evidence-based education policy by quantifying the hypothetical conditions necessary to change an inference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Workshops Society for Research on Educational Effectiveness (SREE) What Would It Take to Change Your Inference? Informing Broad Stakeholder Debate about Research across Systems&#xA;October 8, 2025 (9:00am–1:00pm Central time). In person: Chicago, IL.&#xA;Description:&#xA;Understanding how research can be generated and interpreted across systems requires stakeholders in different systems and levels to communicate clearly about the strength of evidence supporting an inference. Towards that end, this workshop informs discussion about the strength of evidence by imagining the conditions necessary to change the inference.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
