<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KonFound-It! Home on KonFound-It!</title>
    <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in KonFound-It! Home on KonFound-It!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://konfound-project.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Sensitivity in Causal Inference with Kenneth Frank</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2024-12-20-statistical-horizons-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2024-12-20-statistical-horizons-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Learn more and register: https://statisticalhorizons.com/seminars/sensitivity-analysis-causal-inference/&#xA;Explore the first hour of Kenneth Frank&amp;rsquo;s seminar on &amp;ldquo;Sensitivity Analysis for Causal Inference,&amp;rdquo; where he introduces key concepts and sets the foundation for exploring robust causal inference techniques.&#xA;About this Seminar This seminar provides hands-on experience with two techniques for quantifying the sensitivity of causal inferences: Robustness of Inference to Replacement (RIR) and Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable (ITCV). These techniques can be adapted to a range of analyses, including logistic regression, propensity-based approaches, and multilevel models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions About the Application of KonFound-It for Sensitivity</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2023-08-13-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2023-08-13-faq/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This document addresses some frequently asked questions regarding KonFound.&#xA;Questions? Issues? Suggestions? Reach out through the KounFound-It! Google Group.&#xA;See the appendices for background readings and software. For quick reference, visit:&#xA;[Development version of the FAQ](https://www.dropbox.com/s/9eymdekym5g50o7/frequently asked questions for application of konfound-it.docx) Overview of all KonFound commands Main introductory slides for combined frameworks Background There are two basic frameworks for sensitivity analysis employed within KonFound. First is the Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable (ITCV)—Frank (2000).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2020-05-14-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2020-05-14-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to our space about sensitivity analysis. All of the assumptions of statistical analysis rarely hold. So the challenge for the pragmatist is to understand when evidence is strong enough to support action. That&amp;rsquo;s where sensitivity analysis comes in—so we can understand how robust our inferences are to challenges to our assumptions. One example is a statement such as:&#xA;XX% of the estimated effect would have to be due to bias to change your inference about the effect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is robustness important for emerging COVID-19 studies?</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2020-05-12-why-robustness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2020-05-12-why-robustness/</guid>
      <description>As those who work in public policy and health, we seek to help a broad range of people, with a broad range of statistical backgrounds, interpret uncertainty about public health findings regarding COVID-19. We observe that currently, there is little common language for expressing uncertainty. Consider Anthony Fauci&amp;rsquo;s quote (as in Healio on April 29):&#xA;The trial, which began Feb. 21 this year, compared remdesivir with placebo in more than 1,000 patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A 15-minute talk</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2020-05-01-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/post/2020-05-01-presentation/</guid>
      <description>I summarized our current thinking on how robustness analysis can be applied to emerging COVID research in a brief presentation at an online conference entitled &amp;ldquo;COVID-19 and Public Policy and Management.&amp;rdquo; The conference was hosted by the Center on Technology, Data, and Society at Arizona State University, and a recording of the 15-minute talk, entitled &amp;ldquo;Communicating the Robustness of Inferences as COVID-19 Evidence Accumulates&amp;rdquo;, is available here.&#xA;Communicating the Robustness of Inferences as COVID-19 Evidence Accumulates </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About KonFound-It!</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to our space about sensitivity analysis.&#xA;Questions? Issues? Suggestions? Reach out through the KounFound-It! Google Group.&#xA;Purpose All of the assumptions of statistical analysis rarely hold. So the challenge for the pragmatist is to understand when evidence is strong enough to support action. That&amp;rsquo;s where sensitivity analysis comes in—so we can understand how robust our inferences are to challenges to our assumptions. One example is a statement such as:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/faq/</guid>
      <description>by Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, Ran Xu, Spiro Maroulis, Guan Saw, &amp;amp; Josh Rosenberg&#xA;Last updated: 7/5/2024&#xA;FAQ Dev Version&#xA;Introduction This document addresses some frequently asked questions regarding KonFound. See the appendices for background readings and software. For quick reference, see:&#xA;Overview of all KonFound commands Main introductory slides for combined frameworks Background There are two basic frameworks for sensitivity analysis employed within KonFound. First is the Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable (ITCV)—Frank (2000).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>Latest News Announcing Summer 2025 Workshops and Conference Presentations (posted 04/07/25) Conference Presentation: Society for Causal Inference, Friday May 16, 10:15-11:45am ET in Detroit, Michigan — Multi-faceted Approaches to Sensitivity Analysis for Observational Studies&#xA;Topical Workshop: ICPSR Summer Program in Quantitative Methods, July 28-Aug 1 — Sensitivity Analysis: Quantifying the Robustness of Inferences to Alternative Factors or Data&#xA;Workshop: Society for Epidemiologic Research, Tuesday, Aug 5, 12-4pm ET — What Would it Take to Change Your Inference?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Guide</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/guide/</guid>
      <description>PDF Download: August 2025 Practical Guide draft&#xA;Citation: *Frank, K. A., *Saw, G. K., Lin, Q., Xu, R., Rosenberg, J. M., Maroulis, S. J., &amp;amp; Staudt Willet, K. B. (2025). A practical guide to impact threshold of a confounding variable (ITCV) and robustness of inference to replacement (RIR). Michigan State University.&#xA;* Co first authors.&#xA;Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; / [pdf] View the PDF file here. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/publications/</guid>
      <description>Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient. Sociological Methods and Research, 29(2), 147-194. PDF | Web&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., &amp;amp; Maroulis, S. (2023). Quantifying sensitivity to selection on unobservables: Refining Oster’s coefficient of proportionality. White paper. PDF&#xA;Frank, K. A., Lin, Q., Maroulis, S., Mueller, A. S., Xu, R., Rosenberg, J. M., Hayter, C. S., Mahmoud, R. A., Kolak, M.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource Overview</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Tools R package (CRAN version) R package (development version) R Shiny app Stata package Benchmarks: What Works Clearinghouse [BETA] Explanatory Resources FAQ Overview of KonFound techniques Overview of KonFound commands Quick examples Slides quantifying the robustness of causal inferences combined frameworks Slides for comparison of frameworks Resources for Publication Published empirical examples KonFound-It! spreadsheet for calculating indices Publications: Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on the inference of a regression coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/talks/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Talks Quantifying Sensitivity to Selection on Unobserved Covariates: Recasting the Coefficient of Proportionality within a Correlational Framework 2025 Joint Statistical Meetings, Multi-faceted Approaches to Sensitivity Analysis for Observational Studies&#xA;August 6, 2025 (10:30am–12:30pm Central time in Nashville, TN).&#xA;Paper&#xA;Presenters: Kenneth A. Frank, Qinyun Lin, &amp;amp; Spiro Maroulis&#xA;Abstract: Sensitivity analyses can inform evidence-based education policy by quantifying the hypothetical conditions necessary to change an inference. Perhaps the most prevalent index used for sensitivity analyses is Oster’s (2019) Coefficient of Proportionality (COP).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://konfound-project.github.io/page/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Workshops Society for Epidemiological Research What Would it Take to Change Your Inference? Quantifying the Discourse about Causal Inferences in Epidemiology&#xA;August 5, 2025 (12:00–4:00pm Eastern time). Virtual.&#xA;Description:&#xA;Causal inferences are often challenged because of uncontrolled bias. We will turn concerns about potential bias into questions about how much bias there must be to invalidate an inference. For example, challenges such as ‘But the inference of an exposure might not be valid because of pre-existing differences between the treatment groups’ are transformed to questions such as ‘How much bias must there have been due to uncontrolled pre-existing differences to make the inference invalid?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
